仙
境
奇
缘
第一季  第五集
翻译：冰蓝  爱卿遛小鸟  潇湘月影  如是我闻
■
翻译：阿噻  米苏   时间轴：冰蓝  雨之  小萌
校对：米苏  Eowyn  wdjmhs
■
后期：灰灰是菇凉   总监： wdjmhs
没人相信爱丽丝
No one believed Alice
所说的仙境冒险
when she spoke of her adventures in Wonderland,
所以红桃杰克和我带她回去
so the Knave of Hearts and I brought her back
寻找她的真爱
to search for her true love.
他在这里  我能感觉到
He's here. I can feel it.
有人想阻止她
There are those who will try to stop her.
让那个女孩许下三个愿
What we want can't be accomplished
我们的目的才能达成
until the girl's made all her wishes.
但是爱丽丝的伟大冒险
But Alice's greatest adventure
刚刚开始
has just begun.
《仙境奇缘》前情提要
Previously in Wonderland...
也许你能骗过所有人
Maybe you've fooled all these people,
但我知道你的真实身份
but I know who you really are.
人们想要你死
People want you dead.
我没法动了
I can't move.
爱丽丝  出什么事了
Alice, what's happening?
安娜斯塔西娅
Anastasia!
你就打算跳进魔镜吗
So you're just going to jump through some magic mirror?
我们可以为所欲为
We can be whoever we want to be.
下一站
Next stop...
仙境
Wonderland.
你们在干什么
What are you doing?
母亲
Mother.
你跟踪我们到了这里吗
Did you follow us here?
当然是
Damn right I did.
你要和这个废柴
You're going to run off with this...
私奔吗
loser?
是这么回事吗
Is that what's happening here?
这不关你的事
It's none of your business.
我生下了你  亲爱的
I birthed you, dear.
所以如果你打算毁掉你的生活
So if you are going to ruin your life,
这当然和我有关
it absolutely is.
这不是毁掉  妈妈
It's not ruin, mom.
我找到了威尔
I found Will.
我知道
I know.
悲剧就在于此
That's the tragedy.
我想让女儿成为女王
I wanted a queen for a daughter,
但结果她成了什么
but what did I get instead?
一个失败者
A failure.
我终于
I'm happy...
得到了快乐
finally.
和他一起吗
With him?
我这一生
I did not spend my entire life
都在拼命工作
working my fingers to the bone
好让你出人头地
so that you could move up,
可不是为了让你抛弃一切的
only to have you toss it all away.
显然你不是当公主的料子
Obviously you're not princess material,
但我以为你至少也能搭上个贵族
but I thought you could at least land a nobleman.
而不是他  小偷威尔・史卡利
Not him-- Will Scarlet, the thief.
我不是小偷  以后不是了
I'm no thief. Not anymore.
他会给你什么样的生活
What kind of a life is he going to give you?
他什么也不必给我
He doesn't need to give me anything.
我爱他
I love him.
你没法靠爱活着  安娜斯塔西娅
You cannot live on love, Anastasia.
当你以自己惨痛的经历得到教训时
And when you learn that lesson the hard way,
你就会回到原点
you will be right back here where you started.
但你回来时  记得带个桶子
But when you come back, bring a bucket.
因为你要进我家门的唯一方法
Because the only way you'll be coming back inside my house
就是给我倒尿壶
is to empty my chamber pot.
那你们走吧
Off with you then.
至少我还有你妹妹
At least I have your sisters.
别听她的
Don't listen to her.
我会为我们建造新生活的
I'll build us a life--
如果有必要  我会一点点堆砌
brick by brick if I have to.
我爱你
I love you...
是因为真实的你
for who you truly are.
而不是我想让你成为的人
Not for who I want you to be.
来吧
Come on.
再见了  妈妈
Good-bye, mom.
给你披上
There you go...
遮挡雨水和雪花  或者
in case of rain or snow or...
天上掉下的任何东西
anything that might fall from the sky.
真对不起  威尔
I'm so sorry, Will.
如果我没有逼你许下那个愿望
If I hadn't bribed you with that wish,
你就不会...
you would have never...
塞勒斯总说愿望是有代价的
Cyrus always said they had consequences.
现在我明白了
Now I understand.
我会解救你的
I will get you out of this.
如果我能找到塞勒斯  那我们一起就能...
If I can find Cyrus, then together we can...
我在骗谁呢
Who am I fooling?
我都不知道他在哪里
I don't even know where he is.
我知道  好消息吧  亲爱的
Then it's a good thing I do, darling.
也许我们能互相帮助
Perhaps we can help one another.
我为什么要帮你
Why would I do anything to help you?
当时机合适时  人们愿意做什么
You'd be surprised what people are willing to do
会让你大吃一惊的
when the right circumstances present themselves.
你开不出够好的条件让我...
There's not a circumstance you could present that would ever...
连找到
Not even finding out
你亲爱的精灵的关押地也不算吗
where your precious genie is being held?
是啊
Yes.
你不如放低点姿态
So why don't you get down off your high horse,
我们来做笔交易
and we can make a deal?
什么交易
What sort of a deal?
这笔交易能解决我俩都有的一个问题
The sort of deal to handle the one problem we both share--
贾法尔
Jafar.
你们在合作
You're working together.
他怎么是你的问题了
How is he a problem for you?
他只不过是我达到目的的手段  亲爱的
Well, he's simply a means to an end, darling.
但当目的达成时  我得保证
But when that end comes, I need to ensure
我有能力保护自己
I have the power to protect myself.
我可不想和你朋友下场一样
Wouldn't want to end up like your friend here,
对吧
now would we?
他也是你的朋友  曾经是
He was your friend, too, once.
据我所知  不止是个朋友
More than a friend, from what I gather.
或者他也只是你达到目的的手段
Or was he just a means to an end as well?
那就是你的问题  爱丽丝
That's your problem, Alice--
当你该考虑未来时
always dwelling on the past,
却总是沉湎于过去
when really you should be thinking about the future.
你到底想让我做什么
What exactly is it you want me to do?
帮我弄点东西
Help me procure something.
就是一点粉末状的魔法
Just a little bit of magic in the form of dust.
大概一日路程
It's about a day's journey away.
这能保护我免受黑魔法的伤害
And it's going to protect me against dark magic
比如贾法尔那种
such as Jafar's.
你这么想要的话  自己去取
If you want it so badly, get it yourself.
我也想  亲爱的
I would, darling,
但这么强大的东西到现在还原封未动
but there's a reason something so powerful
是有原因的
sits untouched.
要得到它  对多数人来说简直是寻死
Retrieving it, for most, is a suicide mission.
而你认为我会就这么答应以身犯险
And you think I'll just agree to risk my life?
不  至少得给你点好处
No. No, not unless you're properly compensated.
所以我提出这项交易
Which is why I propose a trade.
你把魔尘给我弄来
You get me the dust,
我就帮你找你的精灵
and I'll help you find your genie.
我自己会找  谢了
I'll find him myself, thank you.
可你不知道上哪找
Not if you don't know where you're looking.
贾法尔的塔以魔法隐匿
Jafar's tower is hidden, enshrouded by magic.
没有我的话  你即使站在塔前
You could be standing right in front of it,
也毫不知情
not knowing it's there, without my help.
你想找到塞勒斯  我是你最好的机会
If you want to find Cyrus, then I am your best bet--
也是唯一的机会
Your only bet, actually.
他们对你做了什么
What did they do to you?
今天
Today...
是巨石
it was the giant rocks.
有些甚至跟人一样大
Some of them as large as a man.
他逼我把石头
He makes me move them
从石梯底部搬到顶部
from the bottom of the stone staircase to the top.
为什么
For what purpose?
没理由
None.
那他为什么把你关在这里
Well, then why does he keep you here?
跟你一样
Like you...
我身上有他想要的东西
I have something he wants.
是什么
Which is what?
无所谓
Doesn't matter.
因为他永远都得不到
Because it's something he will never get.
所以我将继续被他惩罚
And so my punishment continues.
不会很久了  老先生
Well, not for long, old man.
因为今天就是我们离开这里的日子
Because today's the day we get out of here.
你确定是这里吗
Are you sure this is the spot?
我一颗浆果都没看到  我快饿死了
I've not seen a single berry, and I'm bloody starving.
上周这里还有很多呢
Yeah, there was a bunch here last week.
我们那天捕到的鱼呢
What about that fish we caught the other day?
-还有剩的吗  -没了
- We got any of that left? - No...
只剩骨头了
Just the bones.
可以把鱼骨在水里浸久一点
We could soak 'em in water long enough...
那就是汤了
and call it soup.
天哪  快看啊
Bloody hell, will you look at that?
这个可以炖出靓汤
This'll make a right fine stew.
别碰
Ah! No! Don't!
这蘑菇会把你变大
Those are the mushrooms that make you grow big.
现在这马车都快坐不下了
We can barely fit in the wagon as it is.
马车太小了吗
The wagon too small for ya?
当然不是
No, of course not.
我们只要这样的就行
It's all we need.
抱歉  亲爱的  我已经尽力了
I'm sorry, luv. I am doing the best I can.
我知道
I know.
我只是以为这里一切会有所不同
I just thought things would be different here.
我第一次听闻仙境时
When I first heard about Wonderland,
以为这里会奇妙美好
I figured that the "wonder" was short for "wonderful",
而不是日日担心怎么过活
not "wonder how we're gonna make it?"
我爱你
Well, I love ya.
我保证  我们会撑过去的
And I promise ya, we will make it.
那些面包闻起来太香了
Ahh! Smell that bread, it smells heavenly.
能给我们一块吗  伙计
Can you spare a loaf, mate?
不行  这是贡品
Can't. It's for the palace.
宫里要办舞会  连面包屑都得端上
There's to be a ball, and every crumb's spoken for.
真是谢谢了
Well, thanks a lot then.
也许我们该走了
Maybe we should go.
但我们还没找到浆果
But we haven't found any berries yet.
不  去舞会
No, to the ball.
我们也该去
We should go.
听说宫殿内部美轮美奂
I hear the palace is dazzling inside.
但有个小问题  我们没有受邀
There's the slight matter of not being invited.
这种问题什么时候能阻挡我们了
Since when has that ever stopped us?
咱俩可以换换环境
We could both do with a little change of scenery.
更重要的是  能吃到面包
And more importantly, some of that bread.
穿这裙子可不行
You know, that dress will never do.
得帮你"借"条新的
We'll have to borrow you a new one.
魔尘在哪
Where's this dust?
大峡谷的另一头
The other side of the Great Divide.
我听说过那地方
I've heard of that place.
那里充满了黑暗
There's a darkness there.
太阳落山之后  哪里都有黑暗
There's a darkness everywhere when the sun goes down.
先说清楚
Just so we're clear,
我会给你弄到魔尘
I'll get you your magic dust.
但一切结束后
But when this is all over...
你最担心的可不会是贾法尔了
Jafar will be the least of your problems.
让我猜猜
Let me guess,
你要让我为对塞勒斯做的事付出代价
you're going to make me suffer for what I did to your Cyrus?
我不是你以为的魔鬼
I'm not the monster you take me for.
我没杀塞勒斯
I didn't kill Cyrus.
再变成囚犯对他来说与死无异
Being a prisoner again is the same as death to him.
但对你不是
But not to you...
所以你才回到仙境
which is what got you back to Wonderland.
你到底想要什么
What exactly do you hope to gain from all of this?
你有权利  财富
You have power, wealth...
还想要什么
what more could you possibly need?
有些东西权利和财富都换不来
There are some things that all the wealth and power cannot get you.
比如呢
Like what?
我们来仙境
We all come to Wonderland
都有所求  亲爱的
looking for something more, darling.
我依稀记得一个身着蓝裙的小女孩
I seem to remember a little girl in a blue dress
渴望着父亲的爱
wanting her father's love.
我和你完全不同
You and I are nothing alike.
我们都渴求自己没有的东西  爱丽丝
We both want something we don't have, Alice.
不同的仅是我们愿意为此做些什么
It's just a matter of what we're willing to do to get it.
再说一遍你看到什么了
Tell me again what you saw.
走廊直通北面
This hallway goes north
有一条只能往下走的楼梯
to a staircase that only leads down.
那守卫呢
And the guards?
只有几个
Only a few...
这令我很担心
which worries me.
怎么说
How's that?
贾法尔警觉性很高
Jafar is vigilant--
总是领先于他的敌人
Always ahead of his enemies.
如果他在里面只有几个守卫的话
If he only has a handful of guards inside...
也许大部分都守在外面
then perhaps the majority of them are on the outside.
那我们等到黄昏
Well, then we wait for nightfall,
趁夜色离开
and make our way out under the cover of dark.
我看到有人试过
I've seen others try.
没人成功
None succeeded.
但我想没人像你这么有决心
But I think none were as determined as you.
秘诀是不要看这些栅栏
Well, the trick is to not see the bars,
而是要看笼子外面的世界
but rather what lies beyond them.
外面肯定有你心爱的人
Surely there's someone out there you love.
家人
A family?
我
I...
曾经拥有自己的生活
had a life once.
可现在那已不再属于我了
It is lost to me now.
那么全新的生活正在等着你
Well, then a new one awaits you.
在瓶子里待了一辈子后  我知道
After a lifetime in a bottle, I know this--
没人应该被人俘虏
No one deserves to be another man's prisoner.
如果我能获得自由
And if I am to be free,
那你也能
then so are you.
这是您要求的物品
The item you requested.
贾法尔
Jafar...
你想要什么
uh... what do you want?
兔子  你引起了我的注意
I'm intrigued by you, Rabbit.
不是要把我当主食吃掉的那种吧
Not in a-a main course kind of way, I hope?
大可安心  你还没有拿来煮的价值
Rest easy, you're far too valuable to cook.
真是松了一口气
Oh, what a relief.
我感兴趣的是为何一个认识爱丽丝那么久的人
I'm interested why someone who's known Alice for so long
还会如此深深地背叛她
would betray her so deeply.
我认识她的时间并不长
I, uh, haven't known her that long.
最多是个熟人而已
I'm more of an acquaintance, really.
你有困难
You have a problem,
而我善于解决困难
and I'm good at solutions.
我能帮你解决你欠女王的债务
I'm offering to help you with your debt to the queen.
但我所要的交换条件是要你帮我
All that I require in exchange is that you help me.
以什么来帮你
With what?
爱丽丝
Alice.
从她还是小女孩起  你就认识她了
You've known her since she was a girl.
我需要知道她的一切
I need to know everything about her--
特别是她曾经深爱过的人
particularly everyone she's ever loved.
那么
Now...
成交吗
do we have a deal?
我的朋友
My friend...
不要往下看
don't look down.
猩猩  我这边需要点东西
Orang! I need something up here.
不
No!
在找我吗
You looking for me?
我还没见过这个地方
I haven't seen this place.
很少有人见过之后  还能活着讲这个故事
Few have and lived to tell the tale.
真会安慰人
Comforting.
那么
Well, then...
魔尘到底在哪里
where exactly is this magic dust?
就在那边
Over there.
越过这峡谷吗
Across the ravine?
-我想这里没有桥或  -恐怕没有
- I don't suppose there's a bridge or-- - Afraid not.
那你的魔法呢
And your magic?
亲爱的  如果我能自己拿到的话
Darling, if I could have gotten it myself,
你不认为我现在就能到手了吗
don't you think I would have by now?
也许不可能拿得到
Maybe it's impossible.
当然不是每个人都能
Not for everyone.
心地纯洁的人将跨越天堑
"The pure of heart shall make the leap."
显然是某种测试
It appears to be some sort of test.
-你怎么知道我能通过  -我不知道
- How do you know I'll pass? - I don't.
但是在我们俩当中
But between the two of us,
我觉得你成功的可能性比我大
I like your chances better than mine.
亲爱的  我有很多东西
I am many things, darling,
但是没有纯洁的心灵
But pure of heart is not one of them.
看看这里
Look here.
甚至比我想象中的还要漂亮
It's even more beautiful than I imagined.
我觉得我穿反裤子了
Me trousers feel like they're on backwards.
不要在扭来扭去了  大家都在看呢
Stop squirming, will you? People are looking.
那是因为我们不属于这里  安娜
That's 'cause we don't belong here, Anna.
这一刻  想象一下我们属于这里
Just for a moment, imagine we do.
如果我们相信  他们也会相信
If we believe it... so will they.
瞧瞧那些吃的
Look at all that food.
就这样浪费实在太遗憾了
It would be a shame to let it go to waste.
你来吗
Are you coming?
等一会吧
In a moment.
-我要到处看看  -好
- I'm just gonna look around. - All right.
我马上就回来
I'll be back.
-你看上去太漂亮了  -谢谢
- And don't you look lovely? - Why, thank you.
亲爱的  我只是羡慕那顶王冠
I was just admiring the crown jewels, darling.
非常想拥有它们
They're simply to die for.
亲爱的  我只是羡慕那顶王冠
"I was just admiring your crown jewels, darling."
亲爱的  你好
Hello, darling.
大部分人会说陛下
Most people go with "Your majesty."
非常抱歉  我不是有意要
So sorry. I didn't mean to--
我知道  没必要道歉
I know. No need to apologize.
女士  请
Milady?
请不要介意
Don't mind if I do.
我很久没参加过正式的舞会了
It's been so long since I've been to a proper ball.
有很多不正式的舞会吗
Are there many improper ones?
真的
Indeed.
我必须承认  我觉得他们
I must confess, I find them...
很无聊
boring.
我非常想换个环境
I'm desperate for a change of scenery.
是的
Yes.
我知道这种感觉
Yes, I know the feeling.
我知道每个在我王宫里的贵妇人
I know every lady in my court.
可为什么我以前从未见过你
Why haven't I seen you before?
我想
I'd say...
不是你还没看仔细
either you haven't been looking hard enough...
就是也许我不是位贵妇人
or maybe I'm no lady.
小偷  小偷  抓住他
Thief! Thief! Grab him!
快走
Come on. Move it!
大人  他的请柬是伪造的
Sire... His invitation is clearly a forgery.
那是我的裙子
That's my dress!
她从我的马车上偷来的
She stole it from my carriage.
一个小偷
A common thief!
骗子
Imposter!
乡下人
Peasant!
我们成功了
We did it.
成功了
Did it?
我们被抓到了
We got pinched.
不  我们偷到东西了
Nah, we did the pinching.
这够我们吃一个礼拜了
This'll last us a week at least.
也不用再穿这些紧巴巴的衣服
And we won't have to bother with them stuffed shirts.
就是字面的意思
Literally.
好吗
Right?
好吧
Right.
走吧  咱们回家  面包还热着呢
Come on, let's go home. Bread's still warm.
我怎么知道你不是在骗我
How do I know this isn't a trick?
如果你就想让我掉下去
That you intend for me to fall?
那我就不得不用掉一个愿望来救命
Then I'll have to use one of my wishes to save my life.
如果我想让你掉下悬崖
If I wanted you to fall off the cliff,
我会直接把你推下去
I'd push you.
心地纯洁的人将跨越天堑
"The pure of heart shall make the leap."
没人能跨过这儿
No one could leap over that,
不管他们的心有多纯洁
No matter how pure their heart was.
除非那才是重点
Unless that's the point.
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
这事没办法做到
There's no way you can do it.
它是条谜语
It's a riddle.
也许它是在比喻什么
Maybe it's a figurative leap--
比如说选择相信
Like a leap of faith.
相信什么
Faith in what?
我不知道
I don't know.
我对你抱有如此大的期望
I had such high hopes for you.
爱丽丝  你再也别想见到精灵了
Alice, you can say good-bye to seeing your genie again.
等等
Wait.
心地纯洁的人将跨越天堑
"The pure of heart shall make the leap."
也许我只需要相信
Maybe I just need to have faith
我心底最纯洁的东西
in the purest thing in my heart--
我对塞勒斯的爱
My love for Cyrus.
我对他的信心将带我跨越天堑
My faith in him will carry me across.
你确定吗
You're quite sure?
当两个人相爱
When two people love each other...
没有什么是他们做不到的
there's nothing they can't accomplish together.
只要那是真爱
If only that were true.
我们的心紧紧相连
Our hearts are entwined.
王后
Queen?!
喂
Hello?!
王后
Queen?!
有人听到吗
Can anybody hear me?!
她失败了
She failed.
回宫吧  女王陛下
Back to the palace, your Majesty.
我才是有权下令回宫的那个
I shall be the one that tells you when we are leaving.
我们失败了
We failed.
是时候回家了
It's time to go home.
抱歉  你刚刚说你想回...
I'm sorry, did you say you wanted to go--
回家
Home...
去找我母亲
To my mother.
不
No.
不行
No way.
我知道事情和我们想的不太一样
Look, I know things aren't exactly how we imagined.
是完全不同
There nothing like we imagined.
你不能回你母亲那儿
You're not going back to your mother's.
她不会收留你的
She'll never let you live it down.
我又没说我们要两手空空地回去
Didn't say we had to go back empty-handed, eh?
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
我们去偷一些珠宝
We are gonna steal the crown jewels.
你说什么
Sorry?
我看到了  在皇宫里
I saw them. They were at the palace.
在主厅的箱子里
In a case off the main hall.
威尔  拜托
Oh, Will, come on.
不是你说为了好的目的去偷窃
Weren't you the one that said it was okay to steal
无伤大雅
if it was for a good reason?
你和绿林好汉们在一起的时候
When you were with the Merry Men,
不正是这么做的吗
isn't that what you did?
劫富济贫
Stole from the rich and gave to the poor?
我们就是穷人  威尔
Well, we are poor, Will.
唯一的不同是没人会施舍我们
Only difference is no one's givin' us anything.
我知道
I know.
你在宫殿东面的阳台下面等我
You'll wait beneath the balcony on the east side of the palace.
我会溜进去
I'll sneak up...
取走珠宝  从阳台上扔给你
take the jewels and drop 'em down to ya.
我们说过不再做那些事了
We said we were done with all that--
偷窃  逃亡
Thieving, life on the run.
因此这才完美
That's why it's perfect.
最后一次
One last time.
然后我们穿过魔镜消失得无影无踪
Then we disappear through the looking glass...
回家后把珠宝卖掉
and sell the riches when we're back home,
也不必担心被抓
without any fear of being caught.
你考虑得很周密
You've given this a lot of thought.
是啊
Yes.
这是过上我们想象的生活的最好机会
Because it's our best chance of living the life we imagined.
我以为我才是
I thought I was your best chance for that.
会成功的
It's gonna work.
我们必须这么做
It has to work.
我们只有一次机会
We only get one shot at this.
准备好了吗
You ready?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
确保我不会拖你后腿
Making certain I don't slow you down.
你有必须要做的事
You know what you must do.
祝你好运  塞勒斯
Good luck, Cyrus.
我不能丢下你
I won't leave you!
没时间争论了
There's no time to argue.
如果贾法尔知道你看着我逃跑
When Jafar learns you witnessed my escape
却没有通知守卫  他会杀了你的
without alerting the guards, he will kill you.
不  他不会
No. He won't.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
相信我
Trust me.
我知道的
I know.
你和我一样清楚守卫的时间表
You're as familiar with the guards' schedule as I am.
如果你现在不离开  你就没机会了
If you don't leave now, you have no chance.
那么  再见了
Farewell, then.
祝你好运
And good luck.
你也是  我的朋友
To you as well, my friend.
她喜欢茶会吗
She enjoys tea parties?
这就是你能给我的秘密吗
That's the insight you give me?
是真的
Well, it's true.
这我已经知道了
I already know that.
实际上  到目前为止你说的一切我都知道
In fact, I know everything you've told me thus far.
别再拖延了
Stop stalling.
她有弱点
She has a weakness.
那就是她在意别人
And that weakness is she cares about people.
我要你告诉我  在仙境中她还在乎谁
I need you to tell me who else in wonderland matters to her--
会为了他们的性命而许愿
Enough so she might wish for their survival.
我很想帮你  但是我真的不知道
Well, I'd like to help you, but I really don't know any--
我很好奇是谁想出"幸运兔脚"这个词的
I wonder who coined the term "Lucky rabbit's foot."
显然不是兔子了  对吧
Certainly wasn't the rabbit, was it?
现在
Now...
也许下一刻
It so happens that for about the next minute,
我可以改变你的困境
I can reverse your predicament.
求求你
Oh, please.
我可以让你再次完整
I can make you whole again.
求你了  做什么都行
Please, anything.
在仙境还有谁是她在乎的
Who else in wonderland does she care about?
滴答
Tick...
Tock.
是有人的
There--there is someone,
但是他们不在仙境
but they're not in wonderland.
有人吗
Hello?!
有人能听见我说话吗
Can anybody hear me?
爱丽丝
Alice!
有人吗
Is somebody there?
爱丽丝
Alice...
谁在哪
Who's there?
爱丽丝
Alice...
快现身
Show yourself!
你好  爱丽丝
Hello, Alice.
很高兴再见到你
It's lovely to see you again.
你是什么妖怪
What... what are you?
我是来帮你的
I'm here to help you.
你知道我在哪儿可以找到魔尘吗
Do you know where I can find the magic dust?
也许吧
Maybe.
我知道很多事情
I know a lot of things.
你能指给我吗
Will you show me?
现在还不行
Not yet.
为什么不行
Why not?
因为你还不够资格
Because you haven't earned it.
告诉我我需要做些什么
Tell me what I need to do.
你知道你必须要做什么  爱丽丝
You know what you have to do, Alice.
我真的不知道
Really, I don't.
在你被锁起来的时候
When you were locked away,
你的梦
your dreams.
记得你的梦吗
Remember your dreams?
是的
Yes.
我梦到了塞勒斯
I dreamt of Cyrus.
为什么呢
Why?
因为我爱着他  我以为他死了
Because I loved him. I thought he was dead.
因为你想要复仇
Because you wanted revenge.
不是
No!
你在梦中要惩罚那些夺走他的人
You dreamt of what you'd do to those who took him.
那不是真的
That's not true.
爱丽丝  我就是你  你骗不了我
Alice, I'm you! You can't lie to me!
你骗不了自己
You can't lie to yourself!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我在帮你达成愿望
I'm helping you get what you want.
-是什么  -杀死红心王后的机会
- Which is what? - The chance to kill the Red Queen.
去啊
Go ahead.
但是她会告诉我塞勒斯在哪
But she's gonna tell me where Cyrus is.
你信她吗
And you believe her?
那么  这里出了什么事
Now then, what is going on here?
动手啊  爱丽丝
Do it, Alice.
我才是你可以信任的人
I'm the one you can trust!
不  你只是一个幻觉  你只是存在在我的脑中
No, you're just a vision. You're just in my head.
我也在她脑中
I'm in her head, too.
我知道你知道什么  我知道她知道什么
I know what you know. I know what she knows.
杀了她  然后我会告诉你塞勒斯在哪
Kill her! And I'll tell you where Cyrus is.
在这下面  魔法是不起作用的
Magic doesn't work down here.
她毫无防御之力
She's defenseless,
就像她带走塞勒斯时的你
just like you were when she took Cyrus away.
她这一生做尽坏事
She's been bad her whole life,
而我们一直都是好人
and we've been good.
我们得到了什么呢
And where's that gotten us?
她是王后  而我们饱受折磨
She's a queen, and we're suffering.
爱丽丝
Alice...
拜托
Please.
动手
Do it!
抱歉
I'm sorry.
但是得有人让你为自己的行为付出代价
But someone needs to make you pay for what you've done.
只是  那不该是我
That's just not going to be me.
爱丽丝
Alice...
恭喜你
Congratulations.
你成功了
You did it.
但她还活着
But she lives.
没错  那就是测试
Indeed, that was the test.
你真的拥有纯洁的心灵
You truly are pure of heart.
你能
Would you?
魔尘
The magic dust!
成功了
We did it.
是的
Yes.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你为什么不杀了我
Why didn't you kill me?
你会得到你想要的一切
You'd have had everything you wanted.
因为我不像你
Because I'm not like you.
不
No...
我想你的确不像
I suppose you're not.
很漂亮  是吗
Pretty, isn't it?
那么来吧  把它给我
Come on, then. Hand it over.
首先  告诉我到哪里去找塞勒斯
First, tell me where I can find Cyrus.
爱丽丝
Oh, Alice.
做一个好人这样的报酬还不够吗
Isn't being such a good person reward enough?
你撒谎了
You lied.
没错
Indeed.
别忘了
Lest we forget...
我们之中有一个心地纯洁
One of us is pure of heart.
是我留给了你一条命
I gave you your life.
不  没有人给我任何东西
No! Nobody ever gave me anything.
我的所有之物  都是我自己争取来的
Everything I have, I had to take.
那么你的所失之物呢
What about everything you've lost?
照顾好自己  爱丽丝
Take care, Alice.
我们很快会再见面的
I'm sure I'll see you again soon.
你不能永远寄望于这些愿望
Can't hold onto those wishes forever...
也不能寄望与塞勒斯重逢
or the hope of seeing Cyrus again.
我会和他重逢的
I will see him again.
你听见了吗
Did you hear that?
如果有人逃走  贾法尔会要了我们的命
Jafar will have our heads if anyone gets away.
我们去看看
Let's go have a look.
谢谢你  兔子
Thank you, rabbit.
这的确对我很有用
I actually think that was helpful.
那我可以走了吗
Uh, can I leave now?
还不行
Not quite.
但我已经把所有事都告诉你了
But I've told you everything.
我也许不需要你再说什么了
There might not be more to say,
但还有很多事需要你去做
But there's certainly more to do.
现在我想出去走走
I'd like to take a trip now.
你可以坐着魔毯去
Well, you've got your carpet.
我想去的地方  只有你能带我去
Where I want to go is a place only you can take me.
开始挖洞
Start digging.
贾法尔  我不能就这么走了
Jafar, I can't just leave.
皇后会察觉到的  然后...
The queen will know something is wrong, a-and then--
现在你为我做事  兔子
You work for me now, rabbit.
还是你需要我再提醒一下你
Or do I really need to remind you?
兔子
Rabbit!
求你  别叫
Please don't.
兔子
Rabbit!
快走
Just go.
什么
What?
去找她  快走
Find her. Go!
兔子
Rabbit!
我知道反抗你是没用的  贾法尔
I know it's futile to resist you, Jafar.
我会遵照你的指示
I'll do what you ask.
你做对了
You made the right choice.
即使找到出路逃出这座塔
Even if you did find your way out of the tower,
你也没办法逃出塔外之物的魔爪
There's no escaping what's beyond it.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
你应该庆幸你没有去亲身体验
Just be glad you didn't find out.
开始挖洞吧
Now dig your hole.
去哪
Where to?
你知道去哪
You know where.
溜进我的舞会是一回事
Sneaking into my ball was one thing.
我倒是很欣赏你的大胆
I rather admire the boldness of it.
但偷我东西就另当别论了
But stealing from me?
为什么要这样
What possessed you?
这有关系吗
Does it matter?
有关系
It might.
在这片国土上  您比任何人都要富有
You have more wealth than anyone in the realm.
丢了也不会在意
You'll hardly miss it.
我比您更需要它们
I need it more than you do.
一个农妇要珠宝来做什么
What does a peasant need with jewels?
一个国王要珠宝来做什么
What does a king need with them?
亲爱的  现实就是如此
That, my dear, is the way it goes.
我的世界充满了财富
My world... filled with wealth,
而你的世界...
And yours...
充满了对财富的渴求
filled with longing.
通常  我们的世界是没有交集的
Generally, our realms don't meet.
您抓住了我
You caught me.
我的命运将会如何
What will my fate be?
这取决于你
That depends on you.
小姑娘  你现在的世界
Ah, there's something about you, girl.
你现在的生活
The life you're in,
并不是你应该过的生活  对吗
It isn't the one you were meant for, is it?
我就只需要这些
It's all I need.
那你为何还要偷盗
Then why are you stealing?
如果你不需要偷盗珠宝
What if instead of stealing these jewels,
而单纯的拥有它们呢
they simply... belonged to you?
您会把它们送给我吗
You'll give them to me?
也许会
Perhaps.
有何代价
At what price?
执子之手
Your hand,
与子偕老
in marriage.
我一直在找一个皇后
I have been searching for a queen.
而你完全符合要求
And you fit the bill.
你所有的...
What you have...
远远不止是美貌
Goes far beyond your beauty.
你的品质极其令人难以琢磨
What you have is what is most elusive--
你的追求远超能力范围的事物
The drive to be more than you are.
这正是统治之道
That is how one rules.
这也是...
And that...
我渴望拥有的力量
is what I desire at my side.
如果我爱的是其他人呢
What if I love another?
我知道  舞会上的那个小伙
Yes, the fellow from the ball.
爱情是神圣的
Love is a noble thing.
但它能支持你们多久
But how far will it get you, hmm?
假设你卖掉它
Let's say you sell this.
得到的钱又能让你们
How long would it last you before you're
挥霍多久
right back where you started?
而不久之后你就会意识到
And that love you cling to,
你所不离不弃的爱情是不够的
It won't be long before you realize, it's not enough.
接下来
And then?
接下来  亲爱的  就太晚了
And then, my dear, it will be too late for you.
快点  快点
Come on, come on.
仙境的人民们
People of wonderland,
容我向你们介绍
I give you...
你们的皇后
Your queen.
安娜斯塔西娅
Anastasia.
对不起
I'm sorry.
很好  塞勒斯
All right, cyrus.
我知道你就在这附近
I know you're out there somewhere.
指路吧
Now show me.
我来找你了
I'm coming for you.
爱丽丝  我来找你了
Alice, I'm coming for you.